Extracting text from: Integrity/INT-500 Administering Your Integrity Software .pdf

Total pages: 61

================================================================================

--- Page 1 ---

 
1.  
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
Administering  
Automation IntegrityTM (AI)  
 
 
AI 500  Training Manual  
 
CIVIL AND CRIMINAL PENALTIES MAY APPLY 
FOR UNLAWFUL OR UNAUTHORIZED USE OF 
THIS DOCUMENT.  
 
⌐ PAS Global, LLC.  All rights reserved.  
CONFIDENTIAL  
 


--- Page 2 ---

 
  
CONTENTS  
 
COURSE DESCRIPTION  ................................ ................................ ................................ ................................ ....................  4 
AUTOMATION INTEGRITY COMPONENTS  ................................ ................................ ................................ ......................  5 
High-Level Overview  ................................ ................................ ................................ ................................ ............  5 
AUTOMATION INTEGRITY NETWORK ARCHITECTURE EXAMPLE  ................................ ................................ ....................  6 
ADMIN UTILITY OVERVIEW  ................................ ................................ ................................ ................................ .............  7 
Running the Admin Utility as an Administrator  ................................ ................................ ................................ ... 7 
Starting the Admin Utility ................................ ................................ ................................ ................................ ..... 7 
LICENSING ISS  ................................ ................................ ................................ ................................ ................................ . 8 
Licensing by Phone  ................................ ................................ ................................ ................................ ...............  8 
Licensing by Email  ................................ ................................ ................................ ................................ ..............  11 
MANAGING YOUR DATABASE  ................................ ................................ ................................ ................................ .......  13 
Creating o r Configuring the Database  ................................ ................................ ................................ ................  13 
Upgrading an Existing Database  ................................ ................................ ................................ .........................  16 
DEFINING THE WEB APPLICATION  ................................ ................................ ................................ ................................  18 
Configuring the Web Application  ................................ ................................ ................................ .......................  18 
Restarting the Web Application  ................................ ................................ ................................ .........................  19 
ASSET MODELS, THEIR USE, HOW TO IMPORT AND UPGRADE  ................................ ................................ ....................  20 
Importing Asset Models  ................................ ................................ ................................ ................................ ..... 20 
Upgrading an Asset Model  ................................ ................................ ................................ ................................ . 21 
Administering Your Integrity Software Suite  
Integrity Software SuiteÖ (ISS) 500  
Document V.5.11.03  

--- Page 3 ---

 OVERVIEW OF ASSET CONFIGURATION  ................................ ................................ ................................ ........................  23 
SERVICE ADMINISTRATION  ................................ ................................ ................................ ................................ ...........  25 
SCHEDULING IMPORTS  ................................ ................................ ................................ ................................ .................  26 
HISTORY OF IMPORTS  ................................ ................................ ................................ ................................ ...................  30 
Viewing Details about Imported Data  ................................ ................................ ................................ ................  31 
Restoring a Previous Version of Imported Data (Roll Back)  ................................ ................................ ...............  31 
Setting an Import Time as the Baseline  ................................ ................................ ................................ .............  31 
CONFIGURE AND MANAGE USERS AND GROUPS  ................................ ................................ ................................ .........  32 
Custom Roles  ................................ ................................ ................................ ................................ ......................  36 
Manage User Groups  ................................ ................................ ................................ ................................ .........  38 
Manage User Accounts  ................................ ................................ ................................ ................................ ...... 40 
USING THE MAINTENANCE TOOLS  ................................ ................................ ................................ ...............................  44 
Perfor ming Database Maintenance  ................................ ................................ ................................ ...................  45 
Configuring Change Tracking ................................ ................................ ................................ ..............................  47 
Configuring Email Notifications  ................................ ................................ ................................ ..........................  49 
Accessing Resources in Trusted Domains  ................................ ................................ ................................ ..........  50 
Integrating the Advanced Dashboard  ................................ ................................ ................................ ................  50 
SYSTEM WIDE SETTINGS  ................................ ................................ ................................ ................................ ...............  52 
Automated Asset Discovery  ................................ ................................ ................................ ...............................  52 
Data Integrity  ................................ ................................ ................................ ................................ .....................  54 
File Upload  ................................ ................................ ................................ ................................ .........................  58 
Vulnerability Management  ................................ ................................ ................................ ................................  58 
TEAMING UP WITH PAS TECHNICAL SUPPORT  ................................ ................................ ................................ .............  60 
 
 
 
 
 

--- Page 4 ---

4 | Course Description   
Managing Your Control System Configuration  ⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  
Suite (ISS) 500  
COURSE DESCRIPTION  
Students will learn the various modules and components of Integrity Software SuiteÖ (ISS) to diagnose 
and administer the PAS Integrity software. Participants will learn and understand the import mechanism 
for configuration files, user administration & security, and database admin istration. Trainees will 
understand how to generate and review log files and interact with PAS Technical Support to 
troubleshoot errors and logging issues.  

--- Page 5 ---

 Automation  Integrity Components  | 5 
⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  Managing Your Control System Configuration  
 Suite (ISS) 500  
AUTOMATION INTEGRITY  COMPONENTS  
High -Level Overview  
 
 


--- Page 6 ---

6 | Automation Integrity  Network Architecture Example   
Managing Your Control System Configuration  ⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  
Suite (ISS) 500  
AUTOMATION INTEGRITY NETWORK ARCHITECTURE 
EXAMPLE  
Automation Integrity is very flexible and can be deployed in many ways, depending on network 
architecture, firewalls, and security policies. This example illustrates working with a DMZ, with a server 
on the Business Network (BN), and Integrity data c ollector on the Process Control Network (PCN). 
Clients can access Integrity application from the Business Network or the Process Control Network.  
 
 
 


--- Page 7 ---

 Admin  Utility Overview  | 7 
⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  Managing Your Control System Configuration  
 Suite (ISS) 500  
ADMIN UTILITY OVERVIEW  
The Integrity installation includes the installation of an Administration (Admin) Utility, which is used to 
perform a variety of administrative and configuration functions, such as validating the product license 
and defining user authentication. This utility should run from only the server where Integrity is installed.  
Running the Admin  Utility as an Administrator  
The Integrity Admin Utility needs to be run as an administrator. Add the Run as administrator property 
to the Admin Utility shortcuts in your Start menu and on your desktop.  
 
To set the Admin Utility shortcuts to run as admini strator:  
1. Right -click on an Admin Utility shortcut , and then click Properties . 
2. Click Properties to display the Admin Utility  Properties window.  
3. Click Advanced . 
4. Check the Run as Administrator  check box.  
5. Click OK to close the Advanced Properties window.  
6. Click Apply , and then click OK to close the Admin Utility Properties window.  
7.  
Starting the Admin Utility  
The Integrity Admin Utility allows an administrator to perform many configuration and administration 
tasks. Run this utility on the server where Integr ity is installed.  
To launch the Admin Utility:  
1. Click Start > All Programs > PAS > Integrity . 
2. Click Admin Utility . 
The installation program also creates a shortcut to the Admin Utility on the desktop.  


--- Page 8 ---

8 | Licensing ISS   
Managing Your Control System Configuration  ⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  
Suite (ISS) 500  
LICENSING ISS  
ò There are two ways to validate Integrity license  
o Telephone  
o Email  
Licensing by Phone  
ò Launch Admin Utility on desktop  
ò On the Product Licensing window of the Admin Utility, Click Begin.  
 
 
 
ò Select I Agree . 
ò Then, click  Next . 


--- Page 9 ---

 Licensing  ISS | 9 
⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  Managing Your Control System Configuration  
 Suite (ISS) 500  
 
ò PAS Customer Care available 24/7  
ò To validate by phone call 281-286-6565 ext. 2  
ò Click Next  
 
ò When on the phone with PAS Customer Care:  
ò Click Phonetic and read the license request code phonetically  


--- Page 10 ---

10 | Licensing ISS   
Managing Your Control System Configuration  ⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  
Suite (ISS) 500  
ò PAS Customer Care will provide you with validation  
ò Enter validation code  
ò Click Next  
 
 
 
ò License validation code accepte d 
 


--- Page 11 ---

 Licensing  ISS | 11 
⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  Managing Your Control System Configuration  
 Suite (ISS) 500  
 
Licensing by Email  
ò Launch Admin Utility on desktop.  
ò Click on Licensing . 
ò Click Send Email . 
ò Select I Agree . 
ò Then, click Next . 
ò Fill in your information.  
ò Click Send Now . 


--- Page 12 ---

12 | Licensing ISS   
Managing Your Control System Configuration  ⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  
Suite (ISS) 500  
 
LicenseInfo.txt  
ò Sent automatically through email after license validation  
ò For licen sing by phone or email  
ò Save in C: \...PAS \Integrity  
 


--- Page 13 ---

 Managing  Your Database  | 13 
⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  Managing Your Control System Configuration  
 Suite (ISS) 500  
MANAGING YOUR DATABASE  
During installation, setup and configure the Integrity database. This section provides the initial 
configuration information.  
 
Creating or Configuring the Database  
To create a new database:  
1. On the Admin Utility window, click the Database link.  
2. Click  the Yes option to specify that a new database will be created.  
3. If you want a location other than the default location for the database files , specify the new 
location  in the Location field. The default location is dependent on the Microsoft SQL Server 
installation location.  
4. In the Database Connection area, indicate the Computer Name (SQL server name) and 
Database Name . If the Microsoft SQL Server installation where the  Integrity database will be 
located  is a named instance, enter the server name followed with a backslash and the instance 
name in the Computer Name field, such as Server \Instance. The Database link in the Admin 


--- Page 14 ---

14 | Managing Your  Database   
Managing Your Control System Configuration  ⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  
Suite (ISS) 500  
Utility is used either to create a new Micros oft SQL Server database for Integrity or to update an 
existing database. The Configure Database Connection Parameters window has a Session State 
Mode panel in the lower portion of the window that is displayed when the Admin Utility is run 
only for the Web version of Integrity. This option allows you to enable or disable SQL Server 
managed session state for the web version.  
Note: The database name must begin with a letter or underscore. Database names can contain 
only letters, numbers, underscores, dashes, and periods. No special characters can be used.  
5. In the Authentication  area, indicate whether Integrity should login to Microsoft SQL Server using 
your Windows account or the specified SQL Server user ID and password. If you select SQL 
Server  mode, type a u ser ID and password.  
Note: For either authentication mode, the user must be a member of the dbcreator (min) or 
sysadmin fixed server role and must be assigned to the db_owner database role. Use SQL Server 
Management Studio to assign the db_owner user role to the account you specify.  
6. If you want to enable Integrity to support a larger number of users , check the Enable SQL Server 
managed session state check box in the Additional Configuration section. The default setting is 
unchecked.  
7. If you want to enable im port rollback , check the Enable Asset Roll Back check box in the 
Additional Configuration section. Asset Roll Back gives users the ability to roll back to a 
previously imported set of data if the most recent import of data is old, invalid, or corrupted.  
8. Click Save . 
9. Click Yes on the Database Creation confirmation message window. When the process is 
complete, a message is displayed.  
Note: If any changes were made to the database settings, a message is displayed on the 
Integrity Admin Utility window indicatin g that the services must be stopped and restarted. Click 
Service Administration to be able to stop and restart the services . 
 

--- Page 15 ---

 Managing  Your Database  | 15 
⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  Managing Your Control System Configuration  
 Suite (ISS) 500  
 
 
 
 
  


--- Page 16 ---

16 | Managing Your  Database   
Managing Your Control System Configuration  ⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  
Suite (ISS) 500  
Upgrading an Existing Database  
The Admin Utility allows you to upgrade an existing database.  
To upgrade an existing database  
1. On the Admin Utility window, click the Database  link.  
2. Click the No option to specify that the existing database should be upgraded, if needed.  
3. In the Database Connection  area, indicate the Computer Name  (SQL server name) and 
Database Name  so Integrity can access the database that contains data for the application. If 
the Microsoft SQL Server installation where the Integrity database is located is a named 
instance, enter the server name followed with a backslash and the instance name in the  
Computer Name  field, such as Server \Instance . 
4. Select whether Integrity should login to SQL Server using your Windows account or the specified 
SQL Server user ID and password. If you select SQL Server mode , type a username and 
password defined within SQL S erver.  
5. If you want to enable Integrity to support a larger number of users , check the Enable SQL Server 
managed session  state check box in the Additional Configuration  section. The default setting is 
unchecked.  
6. Click Save . 
Note: An upgrade of your database  might require you to restart the Integrity Service. If a 
message is displayed on the Integrity Admin Utility window indicating that the services must be 
stopped and restarted, click Service Administration to be able to stop and restart the services.  
 
 

--- Page 17 ---

 Managing  Your Database  | 17 
⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  Managing Your Control System Configuration  
 Suite (ISS) 500  
 
 
 
 
 


--- Page 18 ---

18 | Defining the  Web Application   
Managing Your Control System Configuration  ⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  
Suite (ISS) 500  
DEFINING THE WEB APPLICATION  
The Virtual Directory link in the Admin Utility is used to configure the virtual directory, folder 
permissions, and the ASP.NET worker process account. The Admin Utility also allows you to restart the 
Integrity service and define trusted domain credentials.  
 
Configuring the Web Application  
The Manage Virtual Directory Settings window varies depending on the version of IIS installed on the 
server. For IIS, the following figure shows the available options:  
 
 
To configure the Web application:  
1. On the Admin Utility window, click the Virtual Directory link.  
2. For IIS, you can select a site and port or use the default Web Site and port 80.  


--- Page 19 ---

 Defining  the Web Application  | 19 
⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  Managing Your Control System Configuration  
 Suite (ISS) 500  
3. The Application Name  field defaults to the database name (Integrity). If designat ed, type a 
different name to use for the virtual directory to be used by IIS for user access to Integrity. If 
Integrity is in multiple database mode, this field is unavailable. In multiple database mode, 
the Application Name  must match the database name.  
4. Note the URL for users to access Integrity. The URL is the server name and the virtual directory 
name, such as http://Server/VirtualDirectory.  
5. If you want to use a secure connection (HTTPS) , check the Use a Secure connection check box 
and make sure IIS is s et up for https support.  
6. For Integrity to run properly, permissions must be granted to the virtual directory for the 
account under which IIS runs. This account is referred to as the ASP.NET worker process 
account. Click Yes for the Set permissions option to grant the permissions necessary for the 
ASP.NET account to access the virtual directory.  
The name of the account used for running IIS must be entered into the ASP.NET worker process 
Account name field on the Manage Virtual Directory Settings wind ow. If you select No for the Set 
permissions option, you are responsible for setting directory permissions appropriately.  
If company security policies require that these accounts provided by the .NET Framework be 
disabled or deleted, another system accoun t needs to be created that has the following 
permissions:  
o Read and Write permission on the Integrity application (Integrity) folder.  
o Read and Write permissions on the Reports folder on the same level as the integrity 
application folder. The Reports folder  does not exist until a report is run from Integrity.  
7. Click Save . 
Restarting the Web Application  
The administrator can click the Restart button on the Maintenance window to restart the Web 
Application after a program fault, slow server performance, or ent ry errors. Selecting Update Workflow 
Approvers will synchronize changes made in Windows Active Directory with those set in Workflow user 
assignments.  
Note: Ensure that users are logged off before clicking Restart . Users who are connected to the Integrity 
web server will be redirected to the login page. Any unsaved data will be lost . 
To restart the Integrity Web application:  
1. On the Admin Utility window, click the Maintenance link.  
2. In the Web Application section on the right, click Restart . 

--- Page 20 ---

20 | Asset Mode ls, Their Use, How to Import and Upgrade   
Managing Your Control System Configuration  ⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  
Suite (ISS) 500  
ASSET MODELS, THE IR USE, HOW TO IMPORT AND 
UPGRADE  
Asset models are essentially a set of rules and specifications that ISS uses to represent a single 
automation system (e.g. DCS, PLC, etc.) to import, understand, and present data.  
Asset models must be imported, configured,  and upgraded as required. An Asset Hierarchy Tree is 
configured.  
 
╗ Open Admin Utility from  
the Window Start menu or  
desktop shortcut  
╗ Click on Asset Models  
 
 
 
Importing Asset Models  
╗ Asset Models can be imported only after 
the creation of the ISS database  
╗ Ensure that you have the latest release of 
the Asset Models  
 
 
 
 
 
 
 


--- Page 21 ---

 Asset  Models, Their Use, How to Import and Upgrade  | 21 
⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  Managing Your Control System Configuration  
 Suite (ISS) 500  
 
╗ Select the Asset Models in the left 
pane and click the right 
arrow (>) key.  
 
The asset model is added 
to the Asset model(s) to be imported  list. 
╗ If there are no items l isted in 
the left pane, click the Browse 
button and point to the 
àÆ\DataCollector \Asset ModelsÆ folder in the 
installation location.  
╗ Once all desired models 
have been selected, click the 
Import button.  
╗ When import of Asset Model(s) is 
complete, restart  the IntegrityDataCollector2 
service.  
 
 
╗ Click  Service Administration  (from Admin Utility)  
╗ Select  a Service (field)  
ò Stop and (re)Start when  
IntegrityDataCollector2 
service is selected.  
╗ After  Import(s)  
ò Restart Integrity DataCollector2 service  
ò Ensure that the status shows æRunningÆ  
 
Upgrading an Asset Model  
Open the Asset Model folder that you have received/downloaded from PAS. Follow the instructions in 
the ReadMe.txt files.  


--- Page 22 ---

22 | Asset Models , Their Use, How to Import and Upgrade   
Managing Your Control System Configuration  ⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  
Suite (ISS) 500  
1. Save all the contents of the newest asset model  received from (or downloaded from) PAS 
and replace into the [Asset_Model_Name] folder located in the correct Asset Models path, 
such as the following example location:  
C:\PAS \Integrity \DataCollector \Asset Models \[Asset_Model_Name]  
 
2. Browse to the locatio n of the 
[Asset_Model_Name] folder found in 
step 1  
3. [Asset_Model_Name] selection will 
appear on the left -hand Available 
Asset Model(s) (pane)> select it and 
move it to the right -hand side> Import 
(button).  
4. Click the Import button. The  
importing of the asset  model may 
take up to 5 minutes.  
5. Restart the IntegrityDataCollector2 
service.  


--- Page 23 ---

 Overview  of Asset Configuration  | 23 
⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  Managing Your Control System Configuration  
 Suite (ISS) 500  
OVERVIEW OF ASSET CONFIGURATION  
 
 


--- Page 24 ---

24 | Overview of  Asset Configuration   
Managing Your Control System Configuration  ⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  
Suite (ISS) 500  
 
To add an asset:  
1. In the Admin Utility, click the Asset Configuration link.  
2. Click an asset in the list or click Add to create a new asset. If creating a new asset, verify the asset 
model type.  
3. Complete the following information, and then click Save . The required information varies 
depending on the asset model type:  
4. Import folder : Type the location of the files to import.  
5. Connection definitions : If information from outside data sources is required by this model, edit 
the connection to that data as needed.  
6. Asset properties : Edit properties specific to the asset model as needed as directed by the 
specific asset model Implementation Guide . 
 
Main Components of Asset Configuration  
List of assets  
Asset model type  
and version  
 
Import path of data 
files 
Asset configuration  
Refer to asset  specific  
implementation  guide 
for specifics of 
configuration  

--- Page 25 ---

 Service  Administration  | 25 
⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  Managing Your Control System Configuration  
 Suite (ISS) 500  
SERVICE ADMINISTRATION  
Integrity requires two services and these services must be run under valid domain accounts:  
ò IntegrityDataCollector2  
ò PASWebFileService  
The Service Administration link in the Admin Utility allows you to specify the account username and 
password for each serv ice to use.  
ò If using Windows Authentication mode, the services can be run with Local System.  
ò If using SQL Server mode, the services must be set to use accounts that have been given permission 
to access the SQL server.  
ò By default, the IntegrityDataCollector 2 service runs under the SYSTEM account.  
 
To specify the service accounts:  
1. In the Admin Utility, click the Service Administration link.  
2. In the Service name field, select the service to configure ( IntegrityDataCollector2 or 
PASWebFileService ). 
3. Enter an acc ount that has the necessary access permissions to run the service and access  the 
data files and/or SharePoint data. If necessary, click the Get Accounts button to view all 
accounts on the server.  
4. To preface the account name with the domain name and backsla sh, check the Add Domain to 
Username check box.  
5. Click  Save . 


--- Page 26 ---

26 | Scheduling Imports   
Managing Your Control System Configuration  ⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  
Suite (ISS) 500  
SCHEDULING IMPORTS  
The Import Schedules link in the Admin Utility is used to create a schedule for importing data from each 
data source and to view the status of imports. This link is available only when a database exists as 
specified under the Database link.  
Note: The data import process must b e completed following an initial installation as well as following 
each version upgrade.  
 
To create a schedule:  
1. On the Admin Utility, click the  Import Schedules  link. 
2. Click Add  to open the Schedule Properties window and add a new schedule. This window 
provides several tabs : 
o General : Used to name the import schedule and indicate the server where the data collector 
is located.  
o Sequences : Used to configure import tasks.  
o Schedule : Used to specify the frequency and start time for the import.  
3. On the General  tab,  type a name for the task and the name of the server where the 
IntegrityDataCollector2 service is installed. By default, the Enabled  option is selected to indicate 
that the import should proceed at the scheduled time.   


--- Page 27 ---

 Scheduling  Imports | 27 
⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  Managing Your Control System Configuration  
 Suite (ISS) 500  
4. Click on the Sequences tab to configu re import tasks. This tab allows you to configure sequence 
definitions for multiple assets on a single schedule.  
o Choose an asset. A list of assets that have not been scheduled is available by clicking the 
Schedule button.  
o Select each asset and its definit ion, and then click the > button to move it into the 
Sequence box.  
o Use the up and down arrow buttons to adjust the sequence. The tasks execute one at a time 
starting from the scheduled execution time.  
 
 
 
5. Click the Schedule tab, select the frequency of the  execution of the task, and specify when the 
import should begin. To run the import immediately, select One Time Only and check the Run 
now check box.  
 


--- Page 28 ---

28 | Scheduling Imports   
Managing Your Control System Configuration  ⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  
Suite (ISS) 500  
6. Click OK. Complete these steps until all imports are scheduled and listed on the Schedule 
Imports and M onitor Progress  window. Click the plus sign ( +) next to each import schedule to 
see the import tasks included in it. Notice the Percent Complete column for each task. The web 
application should not be launched until all data imports have successfully compl eted.  
 
 
The Import Schedules link in the Admin Utility allows you to monitor the progress of an import and to 
view the import log, if needed. You can also view the history for a scheduled import.  
To monitor an import:  
1. On the Admin Utility, click the Import Schedules  link.  
2. Click the plus sign (+) next to an import schedule to see the import tasks included in it. The 
Percent Complete  column for each task provides progress information.   
3. If you want to view the import log for a running import , right -click on an asset row, and select 
Import Log Monitor . 
 
 
  


--- Page 29 ---

 Scheduling  Imports  | 29 
⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  Managing Your Control System Configuration  
 Suite (ISS) 500  
The Import Log Monitor window shows the contents of the import log, which can be  scrolled to view all 
the text. Click Refresh to update the contents, and you can search by typing criteria in the Search for 
field. The search text defaults to exception to search for errors in the log.  
 
To view the history for a schedule:  
1. On the Admin U tility, click the  Import Schedules  link.  
2. Right click on the schedule and click History . The Update Summary window opens with details 
concerning imported data for the selected asset model.  
To copy a schedule:  
1. On the Admin Utility, click the Import Schedules  link.  
2. Expand the schedule to be copied by clicking the plus sign (+) next to the schedule name.  
3. Check the check box next to each sequence that should be copied to the new schedule.  
4. Right click on the schedule name and click Save Selected as New . 
 


--- Page 30 ---

30 | History of  Imports   
Managing Your Control System Configuration  ⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  
Suite (ISS) 500  
HISTORY OF IMPORTS  
The History of Imports link in the Admin Utility opens the Review a History of Imports window, which 
displays information concerning imported data for any asset model. This link is available only if a 
database exists as specified under the Datab ase link.  
This window allows you to perform many tasks related to data imports, such as viewing details and 
restoring a previous set of imported data.  
 
 
  


--- Page 31 ---

 History  of Imports  | 31 
⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  Managing Your Control System Configuration  
 Suite (ISS) 500  
Viewing Details about Imported Data  
You can view summary information about imported data and the detailed import log file for that import. 
You can also export the summary information or log file.  
To view an update summary:  
1. In the Admin Utility, click the History of Imports link.  
2. Select an asset model.  
3. Click on a row to select that event from the Import Events table.  
4. If you want to view a summary of the selected data , click Show Summary . 
5. If you want to view the log file with details of the import , click Show Log File . 
6. If you want to save the summary or log file , click Export File . 
Restoring a Previo us Version of Imported Data (Roll Back)  
You can restore a previous version of imported data by using the roll back feature. This feature is 
available only if the database was configured to enable it.  
To restore a previous version of imported data:  
1. In the Admin Utility, click the History of Imports link.  
2. Select an asset model.  
3. Click on a row to select that event from the Import Events table.  
4. Click Roll Back Import . 
Setting an Import Time as the Baseline  
You can establish a set of imported data as a baseline. This baseline can then be used to compare 
against for evaluating imported data.  
To set an import time as the Baseline:  
1. In the Admin Utility, click the History of Imports link.  
2. Select an asset model.  
3. Click on a row to select that event from the Import Events table.  
4. To set the selected event time as the Baseline by which the Import Time Change is compared, 
click Set Import Time as Baseline . 
 

--- Page 32 ---

32 | Configure and  Manage Users and Groups   
Managing Your Control System Configuration  ⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  
Suite (ISS) 500  
CONFIGURE AND MANAGE USERS AND GROUPS  
Create user and group accounts to control who can access the ISS application, and in what capacity.  
The ISS Administrator creates and configures users, groups, and custom roles, specifies the 
authentication method used to login, creates and/or edits users, assigns login names for users, assigns 
one or more role for each  user, creates user passwords (as required), and resets user passwords (as 
required).  
OBJECTIVES:  
ò Navigate and access configuration page for Users and Groups  
ò Specify the authentication method used to configure users, groups, and custom roles  
ò Understand the  difference between Application and Windows authentication  
ò Add a new user and define one or more roles  
ò Understand the difference and purpose of each role (Admin, Power User, User, and Custom Role)  
ò Configure a Custom Role  
ò Add a new Group and define role (i. e. Power User)  
ò Manage User Accounts  
  

--- Page 33 ---

 Configure  and Manage Users and Groups  | 33 
⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  Managing Your Control System Configuration  
 Suite (ISS) 500  
OPEN USERS AND GROUPS IN ADMIN UTILITY:  
ò Open Admin Utility from the Window Start menu or desktop shortcut  
 
 
 
 
 
ò Click on Users and Groups  
 
 
  

--- Page 34 ---

34 | Configure and  Manage Users and Groups   
Managing Your Control System Configuration  ⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  
Suite (ISS) 500  
SPECIFY THE AUTHENTICATION METHOD USED TO CONFIGURE USERS, GROUPS, AND CUSTOM ROLES  
 
 
 
 
 
 
ò Application authentication :  Each user is prompted to login to the application every time it is 
launched. Users must select this option if they intend to run ISS over the Internet. By selecting this 
option, the administrator must add user accounts on this window.  
ò Windows authentication :  When a user launches ISS, the current Windows user account determines 
whether the user is authorized. This mode applies most often when ISS runs within an Intranet since 
users do  not have to explicitly login to the application. Notice that Windows authentication is 
required if the Honeywell Document Manager is importing SharePoint data.  
 
SPECIFY IF THE APPLICATION WILL VALIDATE USERS  
By selecting No (radio button) for this configu ration option the ISS Administrator allows all Windows 
users to access ISS automatically without creating groups and without adding users to those groups  
ò Windows authentication method must be selected for this option to be available  
ò By default, the Yes option is selected  
 
 
 
 


--- Page 35 ---

 Configure  and Manage Users and Groups  | 35 
⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  Managing Your Control System Configuration  
 Suite (ISS) 500  
MANAGE USERS AND GROUPS  
ò Users and Groups can be Local  
ò Select Users or Groups tab  
ò Click Add User or Add Group  
ò Create ISS username or group name  
ò Click OK 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
 
  
oFill in User Information  (section)  
oIgnore Rating  weight  
oClick Choose  Roles  
oUnder Select Primary Role (section)  then  
drop -down to select desired role  
oClick  OK 


--- Page 36 ---

36 | Configure and  Manage Users and G roups   
Managing Your Control System Configuration  ⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  
Suite (ISS) 500  
ISS USER ROLES  
Roles refer to the privileges assigned to ISS users. Typically, an administrator assigns roles when 
creating a new user or group  
Role  Privileges  
USER  Can perform read only operations  
POWER USER  Can perform read and write operations but cannot perform 
administrative operations such as adding or editing user groups and 
accounts  
CONFIGURATION MANAGER  Can perform read and write operations . Can view history, view 
maintenance function, configure workflows and custom properties, 
but cannot add databases or users.  
ADMINISTRATOR  Can perform all operations  
 
Custom Roles  
 
In addition to the User, Power User, Configuration manager, and Administrator roles, custom roles can 
be configured to allow or deny permission to specific assets and object type.  
CREATING CUSTOM ROLES  
ò From Users and Groups, select Yes for the Allow custom roles?  
 


--- Page 37 ---

 Configure  and Manage Users and Groups  | 37 
⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  Managing Your Control System Configuration  
 Suite (ISS) 500  
ò Click the Configure button.  
ò From Custom Role Setting s, click New.  
ò In the Role box, type a name for 
the custom role, and click OK  
ò The Asset Permissions area indicates that 
users of this role can access only specific 
assets. By default, each 
custom role has Deny 
privileges for all assets.  
o Asset : Choose eithe r <All 
Assets> or a single asset  
o Access : Choose to Allow or Deny 
access to the asset(s)  
ò Click Add. Complete these steps as necessary for any additional assets.  
 
CREATING CUSTOM ROLES  
 
 
╗ 
The Object Type Permissions area allows  
or denies permission to specific object 
types within an asset. Choose an asset 
already added for this role.  
o Object type : Choose either  
<All Object Types> or 
a single object type  
oAccess : Choose to Allow or Deny  
access to the object(s).  
oClick Add and Save  


--- Page 38 ---

38 | Configure and  Manage Users and Groups   
Managing Your Control System Configuration  ⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  
Suite (ISS) 500  
Manage User Groups  
Administrators can create multiple user groups and assign users to them. These assigned users assume 
any additional privileges associated with the user group. For example, if a user is assigned to the Users 
role on his or her user accoun t but is also part of a group with the PowerUser role, the user assumes 
privileges associated with the PowerUser role.  
CREATE A USER GROUP  
 
 
 
  
╗ Click on the Groups  tab 
 ╗ 
╗ 
╗ 
Click Add Group  
Type a name for 
the group  
Click OK 

--- Page 39 ---

 Configure  and Manage Users and Groups  | 39 
⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  Managing Your Control System Configuration  
 Suite (ISS) 500  
EDIT USER GROUPS  
╗ Edit the following information as is 
necessary for the group:  
Roles : Click the 
Choose Roles 
button to select a 
role to be applied 
to users in this 
group.  
Users : If user 
accounts have already been added, click the 
Choose Users button to select use rs to assign to 
this group.  
Otherwise, after saving the new group, create 
user accounts, and then edit the group to assign 
users to it.  
 
 
 
 
ò Disable Group : Select  this option to  
disable this  group  
ò Windows  Group:  
Click the Choose 
Windows Groups 
button to select 
Windows Groups 
and/or Windows users 
to assign to this group  
 


--- Page 40 ---

40 | Configure and  Manage Users and Groups   
Managing Your Control System Configuration  ⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  
Suite (ISS) 500  
Manage User Accounts  
If Application Authentication was selected during installation, an administrator should create multiple 
user accounts for ISS access. Users a re required to enter the username and specified password on the 
Login page when they launch ISS or the ISS Admin Utility  
CREATE AND RESET USER PASSWORDS  
ò On the Users tab, click the Add User button.  
ò Type a login name for the user (must begin with one alpha character followed by additional alpha 
and/or numeric values). Special characters are prohibited.  
ò Not case sensitive.  
ò Edit the following information as is necessary for the user:  
o Rating weight: The default is a rating weight of 1 for imported documen ts. If applicable, 
increase this rating weight to increase the effective influence of document ratings.  
o First name: Type the user's first name.  
o Last name: Type the user's last name.  
o Email address: Type the user's e -mail address.  
o Roles: Click Choose Roles t o select the primary role for this user.  
o Disable user: Administrators can disable and re -enable user accounts using this option.  
o Member Of: To assign users to a group, click the Groups tab, edit the group, and click 
Choose Users.  
ò Click Save.  
  

--- Page 41 ---

 Configure  and Manage Users and Groups  | 41 
⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  Managing Your Control System Configuration  
 Suite (ISS) 500  
CREATE AND R ESET USER PASSWORDS  
ò By default, a new user password is set to ôpasswordö  
ò After users are added, they should log into ISS and change their password  
o The ôAllow user to change passwordö option is checked by default  
ò Passwords can contain alphabetic characters and numeric values and must be a minimum of six 
characters  
ò Passwords are case sensitive and cannot be blank  
  


--- Page 42 ---

42 | Configure and  Manage Users and Groups   
Managing Your Control System Configuration  ⌐ 20 20 PAS Global, LLC. All rights reserved.  
Suite (ISS) 500  
CREATE AND RESET USER PASSWORDS  
For users (all roles) to change a password for ISS configured to Application Authentication:  
ò On the ISS Dashboard , click the Change Password icon  
 
 
ò On the Change Password window, type the existing password in the Old Password box  
ò In the New Password box, type the new password  
ò In the Confirm Password box, re -type the new password  
ò Click OK  
ò  
CREATE AND RESET USER PASSWORDS  
To reset a password for ISS configured to Application Authentication:  
ò On the ISS Admin Utility > Users and Groups window, select the designated user  
ò Click the Edit User button  
ò Click Set Password  
ò In the Set New Password window, type the new passw ord, with 6 -10 alphanumeric characters, into 
the New password box. The default is password  
ò Click OK  
 
  


--- Page 43 ---

Error reading PDF: 'charmap' codec can't encode character '\u2713' in position 484: character maps to <undefined>
